Hello friends!
Today we're learning about adverbs.
Adverbs are special words that tell us more about verbs
- they describe HOW, WHEN, or WHERE an action happens.
They make our sentences more interesting and clear!
First, adverbs can tell us HOW something happens.
Look at these examples: The rabbit runs quickly.
The turtle walks slowly.
The bird sings sweetly.
The words 'quickly', 'slowly', and 'sweetly' tell us HOW the
action is done!
Here are more adverbs that tell us HOW: She speaks
softly.
He laughs loudly.
They work carefully.
The children play happily.
Notice how most of these adverbs end with 'ly'?
That's a helpful clue!
Adverbs can also tell us WHEN something happens.
Listen to these: I will go to school tomorrow.
We played cricket yesterday.
She is studying now.
The words 'tomorrow', 'yesterday', and 'now' tell us WHEN the
action happens!
Finally, adverbs can tell us WHERE something happens.
For example: The cat is sleeping outside.
Come here, please!
The birds fly everywhere.
The words 'outside', 'here', and 'everywhere' tell us WHERE the
action takes place!
Great job!
Now you know that adverbs describe verbs by telling us
HOW, WHEN, or WHERE.
Remember: HOW - quickly, slowly, carefully.
WHEN - yesterday, now, tomorrow.
WHERE - here, outside, everywhere.
Start noticing adverbs in your reading!