Hi friends!
Today we're going to learn about homophones.
Homophones are words that sound exactly the same when you
say them, but they have different spellings and different meanings.
Let's explore some fun examples!
Let's start with 'I' and 'eye'.
When I say 'I', I'm talking about myself.
But 'eye' is the part of my body I use
to see!
They sound the same, but mean different things.
For example: 'I can see with my eye.'
Here's another pair: 'son' and 'sun'.
A son is someone's child - like you are your
parents' son or daughter.
But the sun is the bright star in the sky
that gives us light!
Listen: 'The son played in the sun.'
Let's try 'see' and 'sea'.
When you 'see' something, you're looking at it with your
eyes.
But the 'sea' is the big ocean with water and
fish!
Here's a sentence: 'I can see the blue sea from
the beach.'
Here's a fun one: 'ate' and 'eight'.
'Ate' is what you did when you finished eating your
food.
'Eight' is the number that comes after seven!
Can you say this: 'I ate eight bananas for breakfast!'
Great job!
Now you know that homophones sound the same but have
different spellings and meanings.
Remember: 'I' and 'eye', 'son' and 'sun', 'see' and 'sea',
'ate' and 'eight'.
Can you think of more homophones?
Keep practicing!