Hello everyone!
Today we'll learn about the Present Progressive Tense.
This tense helps us talk about actions that are happening
right now, at this very moment.
It's like taking a photo of what someone is doing!
The Present Progressive Tense has a simple formula: We use
'am', 'is', or 'are', then add the verb with 'ing'
at the end.
For example: I am playing.
She is reading.
They are dancing.
Let's see how it works!
Let's start with 'I'.
When I talk about myself, I use 'am'.
Right now, I am studying in Grade 6.
I am learning grammar.
I am having fun!
See how we add 'ing' to the verbs: study becomes
studying, learn becomes learning!
When we talk about one person, like 'he', 'she', or
'it', we use 'is'.
Look: My friend is reading a story book.
The teacher is writing on the board.
The cat is sleeping on the mat.
All happening right now!
For 'we', 'you', and 'they', we use 'are'.
Listen to these: We are playing a board game.
You are listening to this lesson.
They are running in the park.
All these actions are happening right now!
Excellent work!
Now you know the Present Progressive Tense.
Remember: Use 'am' with I, 'is' with he/she/it, and 'are'
with we/you/they.
Then add 'ing' to the verb.
Now you can describe what's happening around you right now!