Once upon a time, there was a young man named
Raman.
He was the son of a wealthy landlord, but he
was very lazy.
He didn't want to work.
Instead, he spent all his time reading books about magic,
hoping to find a way to turn dirt into gold.
One day, a wise sage visited the village.
Raman rushed to him and asked, 'Master, is there a
magic potion that can turn things into gold?' The sage
smiled and said, 'Yes, I know of such a potion.
But it requires a special ingredient.'
'You must plant banana trees,' said the sage.
'And in winter, you must collect the morning dew from
their leaves.
When you have five liters of this dew, bring it
to me, and I will make the potion.'
Raman went home and started planting.
He planted hundreds of banana trees.
Every winter morning, he woke up early to collect the
tiny drops of dew.
It took him six long years to fill the bottle.
While Raman worked in the fields, his wife took the
bananas to the market.
The crop was so good that she sold them for
a lot of money.
Soon, their house was filled with wealth from the harvest.
Finally, Raman took the bottle of dew to the sage.
The sage chanted some words and sprinkled the dew on
a copper vessel.
But nothing happened!
Raman was furious.
'You cheated me!' he cried.
The sage smiled and called Raman's wife.
She opened a chest full of gold coins.
'Look,' said the sage.
'This is the gold you grew with your hard work.
There is no magic potion.
Hard work is the only magic.'