It was a quiet night in the village.
Everyone was asleep, except for one couple.
The wife whispered, 'Ssssh!
Listen!
Somebody is trying to get in.'
A thief slipped through a cracked window into the house
while the couple slept, his intentions unknown.
The husband whispered to his wife, 'The thief might be
armed, so we must trick him into calling the village
kotwal.' She nodded, ready to act.
The husband asked his wife, 'If we have a son,
what shall we name him?' 'We will call him Rama,'
she replied.
'But what if he goes out to play and is
far away?' asked the husband.
'How will you call him back?' The wife smiled and
said, 'I will call him like this.' She called out
softly, 'Rama?' Then she raised her voice, 'Rama!' Finally, she
screamed at the top of her lungs, 'RAMA!
RAMA!'
Rama, the village Kotwal, was patrolling nearby.
He heard his name being called desperately.
He ran towards the house.
Rama burst in and caught the thief.
'Oh, Oh!
Some thief has dug his way into this house!' The
thief trembled, 'Please, let me go!'
The villagers woke up and helped catch the thief.
The couple thanked Rama.
'Your clever trick saved you,' Rama said.
'You called the right name at the right time!'